http://aias.org.uk/privacy-policy/

Skip to content
Introduction
The Anglo Israel Archaeological Society (AIAS) is committed to protecting and respecting your privacy. We aim to be clear when we collect your data and not to do anything you wouldn’t reasonably expect in relation to that data. This Policy explains when and why we collect personal information, how we use it, the conditions under which we may disclose it to others and how we keep it secure.
We regularly review this Policy and may change it from time to time so please check this page occasionally on our website to ensure that you are happy with the changes. By using this website, you agree to be bound by this Policy. Any questions regarding this Policy and our privacy practices should be sent to the Society’s secretary. You can do this by email to the secretary of the society  or by telephone: (+44) 020 8349 5754 or by writing to: The Secretary, Anglo Israel Archaeological Society, 2nd Floor, Supreme House, 300 Regent’s Park Road, London N3 2JX.
Who are we?
The Anglo-Israel Archaeological Society (AIAS), founded in 1961, shines a light on the ancient remains of the Holy Land and wider Near East from prehistory to the Ottoman era.
Through lectures, museum visits, our international journal, student grants and the latest news, we share and promote a passion for the rich archaeology of Israel for everyone. AIAS is a non-political, cultural charity.
Our legal basis for processing data
Organisations are permitted to process data if they have a legal basis for doing so. AIAS may process your personal data on the basis that:
You have given your express and informed consent to the processing; and/or
The processing of personal data is necessary in relation to a contract or agreement that you have entered into or because you have asked for something to be done so you can enter into a contract or agreement.
Where you have given your consent to AIAS processing your personal data, we are required to keep a record of your consent. You can modify or withdraw this consent at any time by notifying us in writing, although this may affect the extent to which we are able to interact with you in the future.
From where do we collect information about you?
We collect your personal data principally from membership application forms. We may also be in possession of debit or credit card details if you pay by card for a publication or admission to an event that we host.
What type of information do we collect about you?
Typically, the personal information that we might collect about you could include:
Your name, address, telephone number and email addressYour bank account details and/or credit card detailsIf you use our website, your IP address
How do we use your information?
We will use the information that you have given us to:
Process your application and collect payment for membership of AIASTo communicate with individuals to advise them of events organised by AIASTo send copies of the AIAS journal Strata to membersTo pay for other publications or for entry to eventsTo populate an annual members list.
AIAS online
Like many other websites, the AIAS website uses cookies. ‘Cookies’ are small pieces of information sent by an organisation to your computer and stored on your hard drive to allow that website to recognise you when you visit. They collect statistical data about your browsing actions and patterns and do not identify you as an individual. This helps us to improve our website. It is possible to switch off cookies by setting your browser preferences.
How long do we keep your information?
We review our retention periods for personal information on a regular basis. We are legally required to hold some types of information to fulfil our statutory obligations (for example the collection of Gift Aid). We will hold your personal information on our systems for as long as is necessary for the relevant activity, for as long as is set out in any relevant contract you hold with us or for as long as is set in our retention schedule. If you would like to know how long we keep your information for, please contact the Secretary (secretary@aias.org.uk).
How do we keep your information safe?
When you give us personal information, we take steps to ensure that there are appropriate technical measures in place to protect it.
Who has access to your information?
AIAS will not sell, share, or rent your information to third parties without your express consent.
Your rights
You may request details of personal information which we hold about you. Any such request must be submitted in writing. Once AIAS is satisfied that that you are entitled to this information, you should receive a response within 30 days.
You, as the data subject, may request deletion of your data at any time in writing, subject to any overriding legal requirement for its retention. You may also choose to restrict the collection or use of your personal information, but this may inhibit or limit the way in which AIAS is able to interact with you. You may, at any time, change your mind about what information we hold about you, or if we continue to hold it at all, subject to any legal obligation on AIAS to retain data.
You are responsible for the accuracy of data you have provided to AIAS. If you believe that any information we are holding on you is incorrect or incomplete, please write to us as soon as possible. We will promptly correct any information found to be incorrect.
You have a right to choose whether or not you wish to receive information from us. If you do not want to receive direct marketing communications from us, then you can select your choices by ticking the relevant boxes situated on the form on which we collect your information. You can update your preferences using the form at the end of this policy.
How you can access your information
If you would like to access the information that we hold about you, please send an email to secretary@aias.org.uk or write to The Secretary, Anglo Israel Archaeological Society, 2nd Floor, Supreme House, 300 Regent’s Park Road, London N3 2JX.
Visit us on Facebook
Search for:
Search
Online lectures In May 2020, the AIAS public lecture programme returned, with a series of online lectures replacing our usual London and Manchester series.
Recordings of past sessions can be found at http://aias.org.uk/lecture-summaries-2020/
We do plan to resume our live lecture series in the future, once we are  advised that it is safe to do so. For now, you can join us virtually, from the comfort of your own homes.
Visit us on Facebook to find out about forthcoming online events.
Introducing the E-Strata Newsletter Our first newsletter has just been published – we’re calling it E-Strata. Have a look, and tell us if you like it!
Strata 37 (2019) now available See the Table of Contents from our latest issue of Strata. All AIAS members receive a copy of the journal, published annually. Why not ask your library to become a subscriber?
Annual Travel Grants Due to current travel and work restrictions, the AIAS is currently suspending its 2020 travel grant programme. Watch this space for further updates.
Recent News
Student Reports 2019
20 March 2020
Archaeological Report from Israel – December 2019
24 February 2020
Tags
Acre
Arabic
